{
    "id": "d93ea00c0dba4e88bbfb1b3c14f2bb66",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. he is not at home.",
            "description": "That can be omitted after suppose.",
            "answers": [
                "suppose",
                "suppose that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "fbcef225eb864f6c88592eaf49fbf998"
        },
        {
            "question": "We hoped …………………………….",
            "description": "We use a that-clause after hope.",
            "answers": [
                "that you would succeed",
                "you to succeed"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "cd04cf8d110c442e9181e8178e4cdb31"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………………. that he has met your dad.",
            "description": "Tell is used before a personal object.",
            "answers": [
                "tells",
                "says",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "fc64084eb5e243ddade0d0542aa7d34d"
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher ………………………….. he was very busy.",
            "description": "Tell is used before a personal object.",
            "answers": [
                "said",
                "told",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f482620f725c46ad993e10856454ae8e"
        },
        {
            "question": "She suggested …………………………………to the park.",
            "description": "We use a that-clause after suggest.",
            "answers": [
                "us to go to park",
                "that we should go",
                "us we should go"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f107bd58446f4587bccd0e8ae8aef0b3"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………………. me that he was coming on Sunday.",
            "description": "We use tell before a personal object. ",
            "answers": [
                "said",
                "told",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ff1bc3c29ee54cd4920ce0a6272bf4aa"
        },
        {
            "question": "I advised him …………………………….",
            "description": "Advise can be followed by to + be + adjective.",
            "answers": [
                "to be careful",
                "that be careful",
                "that he be careful"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "223ce271fe364fc484f5c4d23302de91"
        },
        {
            "question": "He promised us ………………………….. there at five.",
            "description": "We use a that-clause after promise + object.",
            "answers": [
                "to be",
                "that he will be",
                "that he would be"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1f4f39352a4d49b5ad3dc664a7ae48d0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nobody knows when ………………………………. arrive.",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "will he",
                "he will",
                "he would"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f0786c8e7ccd4215a3042236fbbd7bb6"
        },
        {
            "question": "Tom could not figure out what …………………………… do next.",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "he should",
                "should he",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "cc0c1c05018d48709f1c10d69e4e7f54"
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me ...............................................",
            "description": "Ask can be followed by object + to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "to go",
                "that I go"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e8d2a477749b497e9dcfcbc5efafb8ab"
        },
        {
            "question": "They made him .............................................. for hours.",
            "description": "Make + object is followed by infinitive without to. ",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "waiting",
                "to wait"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ce771dfaf23046728d5a3727c6763a32"
        }
    ]
}